[SPEAKER_02]: Was he pleasant at all with you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Could he be pleasant?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yes, he could be a perfect gentleman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was perfectly mannered.
[SPEAKER_00]: The situation eventually came up, I let my little finger stick out when I threw my change of pace.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a dead giveaway to smart batters.
[SPEAKER_00]: Next time he pitched against Detroit, I said to him before he went to mound, now wait when Cobb comes up and shit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Situation called that knuckle of his.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never said anything of the East kind.
[SPEAKER_00]: I want you to let your little finger stick out just as if you're going to throw the knuckle, but don't throw it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never told me anything of the kind.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did these things.
[SPEAKER_00]: I learned all these things myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: What I want you to do is aim your pitch at the center of Cobb's forward and throw that ball just as hard as you can.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, don't worry about hitting him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's got the best eyes in the league.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pitchers have been throwing at his head for 15 years, and nobody's hit it yet.
[SPEAKER_00]: So continued Cobb.
[SPEAKER_00]: When the situation came up, Waite let his little fingers stick out so Cobb could see it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he decked him, but good.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the dust really flew at the home plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: When Cobb got up and brushed himself off, he had the most puzzled look on his face as he peered in at Hoyt in the mound, but not for long.
[SPEAKER_00]: When Waite did the same thing and decked him a second time, Cobb just sat there on the ground, smoothing
[SPEAKER_00]: the day with the palm of his hand, and suddenly looked out at Hoyt and hollered, you must be rooming with Mays.
[SPEAKER_00]: You must be rooming with Mays.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a good story.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a good story, but every damn word, and it's a lie, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nothing like that ever took place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where he gets those ideas, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just got old.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a great pitcher there, there's no doubt about it, and if he had paid... More happened to Carl, it strikes me that when a fellow...
[SPEAKER_00]: When a fellow becomes beset... Well, that's the wrong way to start this thought, anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: Certain fellows seem to have...
[SPEAKER_00]: careers or a lifetime or a life persistency of ill luck or peculiar happenings or things that they're not responsible for and they become victims of some lifestyle that is unanswerable.
[SPEAKER_00]: There is a story in there about his wife died.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I know this, how you can get in trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, he never mentions these things.
[SPEAKER_00]: His wife lived in Springfield, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know whether you knew that or not, Frederica.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were in Chicago and I had had a fight with Brick Owens, the umpire, and I was suspended.
[SPEAKER_00]: for three days.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we were in the outfield running down the boards.
[SPEAKER_00]: I could work out before the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Carl came up to me and he said, that son of a bitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, who are you talking about?
[SPEAKER_00]: The Huggins.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, what's the matter, Carl?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said,
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he says, you see, Frederica is having the...
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, Jesus, I don't know what to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know whether to go home and walk out on a ball club or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, this is a true story.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, well, why?
[SPEAKER_00]: What happened?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well, you see, Frederica, last night, the baby was being born and got stuck on the way out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, I don't know what you call that.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's some name for that.
[SPEAKER_00]: They can't get the baby in or out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, I asked Hug of...
[SPEAKER_00]: to let me go home and wouldn't let me go.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, I don't know if Federico's going to die or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: She's in a very serious condition.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I said, well, hold a fort a minute.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was suspended.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had, oh, I didn't, I'm getting ahead of myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had an exhibition game to play in Toronto the next day after Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, uh,
[SPEAKER_00]: Hug was going to have Carl pitch the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Carl was in bad with Hug, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so I went in to Hug.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, look, Hug, Carl has this trouble with his baby and his wife is dying.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, nice, you can't do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll pitch the game in Toronto.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got nothing to do and I'm suspended.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, as a result, they did let Carl come home.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, on the other hand, our ball club in Toronto made a joke out of the game, and factually, I did not.
[SPEAKER_00]: I tried to pitch the game for about three or four innings, but we had Hinky Haynes and not our regular shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had guys playing out of position.
[SPEAKER_00]: They threw the ball over the head of the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: We committed something like seven errors.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then after a while, and I thought, to hell with this, they're not even trying.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe Dugan, they excused him from the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: He leaped over the, there used to be a little wall that led into the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: leaped over the wall, he limped as far as the club, as this place he had to jump over, then he jumped over it, and all this sort of thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And by God, they held my pay up for a month.
[SPEAKER_00]: They said I wasn't trying in all this business, because I volunteered to help a guy that was in trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, as I say, then it says in this book here that Frederica died of some ear or throat infection or something later on, I'm not sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you take that book with you.
[SPEAKER_00]: I appreciate that.
[SPEAKER_02]: There have been many to get it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I have quite a baseball library, but I don't have that one.
[SPEAKER_02]: I haven't seen it on sale anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: The fellow came here and won over 20 games right away the next year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he won 20 games in 19 games.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was pretty smart, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Very.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Carl was a very smart fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: Carl dressed well, acted well, was a perfect gentleman off the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: You would never believe to talk to him that he had these altercations on the field, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just had a quirk in his personality.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got a lot of old baseball, I've got some baseball magazines going back to about 1920.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not a complete run of them, but quite a few of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: And in the, must be in the November or December issue of 1920, he's got an article by Mays about the Ray Chapman incident, which happened just a couple months before.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's very well written.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's trying to explain his position on all this.
[SPEAKER_02]: I always became a Carl Mays fan reading that explanation, because how he understands that people don't like him, that he has caused trouble, and he's sorry about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He just can't seem to do much about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: But then going on to this particular game, this pure accident, it was very well put.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I would think for a guy
[SPEAKER_02]: as much on the spot as he was then to be able to think and write so clearly was quite a feat.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a way of alienating people, the fellas he played with.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he seemed to be, he felt himself to be an object of, object of dislike and he set himself apart a great deal from the other players.
[SPEAKER_02]: Does he take good care of himself?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Carl is not around.
[SPEAKER_02]: I read so much in this about how the Yankees were so disciplined on the field, but then they went on the turf and got off the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that exaggerated?
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that my piece?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I think there's something in here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I mean, is that...
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know where it is now.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think I read it here somewhere.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't make it special.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't mark it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think you should ask about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were the best disciplined ball club on the ball field that I've ever known.
[SPEAKER_00]: And off the field, they... Well, only a handful, but they were no worse...
[SPEAKER_00]: They were no better or worse than any insurance salesman or anybody else that there was... You see, what you must recognize, they played during Prohibition.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was the Roaring Twenties, and they lived according to their times.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you go out in crowds very often after a game?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no, no, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: They never went in crowds.
[SPEAKER_00]: A couple of fellas might go together.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was none of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was none of that at all.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it sounds like it was a pretty well-disciplined team.
[SPEAKER_02]: Off the field too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And another thing, I've got to say this, there might be instances where you might read a Ruth patronizing some houses down in St. Louis or around in different places, which more or less is the truth, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: But by and large, the team
[SPEAKER_00]: was a very highly intelligent, well-educated team that traveled in the best of company.
[SPEAKER_00]: The best of company.
[SPEAKER_00]: With fine people.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fine people.
[SPEAKER_00]: People, business heads.
[SPEAKER_00]: There weren't any of this
[SPEAKER_00]: They were all, everybody, Dan Nolan in Cleveland, the Wurlitzer agent up there, and Henry Dreer, the Dreer Piano Company, and all these different people.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Cronks and the Dowdells and these people in St. Louis, Toppen and the president of the country clubs and things of that kind.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were a real high-type ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had his moments, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wally Pitt.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wally was a university graduate, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: He came from a very well-to-do family.
[SPEAKER_00]: His father was a wholesale butcher in Grand Rapids, I believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were in the meat business, and Wally Pipp was in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: That family was very well-off and very well-thought of.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a pretty fine first baseman, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wally Pipp was a good bloke, really.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you in the park where Whitey Witt got hit in the head that day, the potpourri?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got hit in the head.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't know he didn't step on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't step on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It didn't come up and hit him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody threw it.
[SPEAKER_00]: The crowd was standing around the outfield.
[SPEAKER_00]: They threw it out of the crowd.
[SPEAKER_00]: Paul was headed into the crowd, and somebody sculled him with a bottle.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Charlie O'Leary rubbed the blood all over his face to make him look like his head was cut off, and then they carried him in, and that threw a pall over the entire crowd, and either the guy that threw that bottle may have lost a Brownsville pennant.
[SPEAKER_00]: But boy, they, the crowds,
[SPEAKER_00]: They seemed to deflate right away.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Whitey got the Edo Verbshock and beat them in the final game of the series.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in 22.
[SPEAKER_00]: But there's so much that's true and so much that's untrue, and it is discouraging after a while to read all that you read about.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a great deal of truth in a great many things that's never been printed that perhaps is just as grievous as some of the things that are untrue that have been printed.
[SPEAKER_00]: And my objection is to the people who don't know, who actually don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, there's another thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: As I get older, the great danger, the great danger is...
[SPEAKER_00]: I told Bob Kramer, when he was doing the book, Babe, and he said he was going to interview Joe Dugan and these different people, I said,
[SPEAKER_00]: Well Dugan was my roommate for years and I said, well look, you see you talk to Dugan, and Dugan is a fellow who likes his drinks.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dugan is not an alcoholic, but he drinks a great deal.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he's not an alcoholic, he's a guy who can handle his liquor.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's the kind of a fellow who lives in that atmosphere and he would, his favorite stories or his would be embellished anecdotes about Ruth, and he's drinking if you were going to write about Ruth, and he would think that's funny.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they would be all shallow, shallow recitations.
[SPEAKER_00]: There would be no depth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ruth had a certain depth that people,
[SPEAKER_00]: that's never been printed.
[SPEAKER_00]: I haven't read Cramer.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: The more I read Cramer's book, the less I liked it, really.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because he got finely into four-letter words that were ridiculous.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Ruth was profane.
[SPEAKER_00]: He did use four-letter words, but coming from Ruth, he paid no attention to them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know why, but there are some people like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Ruth was...
[SPEAKER_00]: You just became tolerant of him, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a capacity of largesse in some ways that carried him so far above.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was such a unique guy that you tolerated him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Roger Peckinpah tells me about his being traded away from the Yankees after the 1921 season.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says that Ruth may have been responsible because Ruth was boosting Peck for Huggins' job.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they couldn't get rid of Ruth, so they had to get rid of Peckinpah.
[SPEAKER_02]: See what I mean there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Ruth didn't get along too well with Huggins, I'm not sure, but it may have been part of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he was kind of surreptitiously building up Peckinpah to be manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: That could be.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I don't think Ruth... You see, there's one...
[SPEAKER_00]: fallacy in that story.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't connive like that or conspire?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's one fallacy in that story.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ruth, at that point in his existence, you see, Scott came to us in 1922, and that's only the second year that Ruth was at all popular.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Ruth wouldn't have the initiative, nor the gumption,
[SPEAKER_00]: nor the audacity to brace the front office on behalf of anybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see what I mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: It's too early for them, really, as far as being established.
[SPEAKER_00]: Certainly.
[SPEAKER_00]: And furthermore, there was a definite split in the
[SPEAKER_00]: The relationship of Tillinghast-Huston, Colonel Huston and Colonel Rupert, the two colonels didn't get along at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Colonel Huston was very anti-Huggins, and Colonel Rupert was pro-Huggins.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Huston didn't like Huggins.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I say didn't like Huggins,
[SPEAKER_00]: Except that in meaning that he didn't like him as a man or a personality.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't like his operation.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he thought that there should be somebody... Well, as I understood that, Houston wanted Robinson to manage the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: And while he was... Houston was in France.
[SPEAKER_02]: Rupert went ahead and hired Hugginson to go... That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Robinson and Houston and that bunch used to get on at Dover Hall every fall hunting.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah?
[SPEAKER_02]: George Stallings, did he own that place?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not Dover Hall.
[SPEAKER_00]: Robinson owned it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Ruth used to go down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Quite a group used to go down there, hunting down there in Dover Hall.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've told, I think, in one of your range stories, by going into Rupert's office in the brewery there,
[SPEAKER_02]: for contract talks?
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you in there very often?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was it like going up to his office in there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you had to go four floors.
[SPEAKER_00]: His office was on the fourth floor, and it was the, of course, when you went into the place, first of all, you went into a long marble, brown marble, I think it was brown marble, brown marble hallway, and you didn't see much of the
[SPEAKER_00]: brewery because you went up into the elevators and all the woodwork was rosewood or anishin palm and all that sort of thing and the brewery was immaculate.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could eat off the floor.
[SPEAKER_00]: You wouldn't think it was a brewery.
[SPEAKER_00]: And moreover, it was during Prohibition most of the time, see, and the brewery wasn't operating at full strength either.
[SPEAKER_00]: How could it operate at all, I wonder?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, because they were making near beer, and you've got to make real beer before you can make it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then you've got to extract the alcohol or something, and you have to reduce it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And to make near beer, make 3-2, or whatever they permitted.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, but Rupert's office was on the fourth floor and his office was bigger than this whole apartment here and all well carpeted and well rugged.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if it was carpeted but it was well rugged and a sumptuous place.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the king.
[SPEAKER_00]: And look, Rupert himself was immaculate.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was one of the best-dressed... Yeah, I was going to say, reflected his own personality.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, one of the best-dressed men in his rolling stockings.
[SPEAKER_00]: He operated as Rolls-Royce.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Rolls-Royce looked like it was just bought when he was about 10 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was that way about everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a heavy accent.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yes, but the more excited he got, the heavier the accent became.
[SPEAKER_02]: He spoke to you in plurals?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Roots, baby roots.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll tell you one good story about the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess it was in the 21 when they're winning the first pennant.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's offered somebody the brewery if you get a hit.
[SPEAKER_02]: I give you the brewery.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he never got the brewery.
[SPEAKER_00]: And yeah, he did, down in the bullpen.
[SPEAKER_00]: I give you the brewery.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, I give you the brewery.
[SPEAKER_00]: Win the pennants, I give you the brewery.
[SPEAKER_02]: And one of the stories I like is the time you were shooting for your first 20 game season.
[SPEAKER_02]: Had that big lead and they'd bring Ruth in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jesus Christ, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the book, the only game he got a game, they gave it to him.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, that's the official score.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess they didn't have too much choice there.
[SPEAKER_02]: It wasn't very fair.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's something.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now it's their judgment.
[SPEAKER_02]: What happened to the Yankees in 25?
[SPEAKER_00]: Me just fell apart, we got started bad, we had the best ball club in the league and I finished 7th.
[SPEAKER_00]: That ball club did wear out though, Evan Scott wore out in the shortstop and Aaron Ward got to be quite a second baseman and he was a hell of a second baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got to be a little bit on the
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and Whitey Witt was about through, or was through, and Scotty and Warty, we needed catching, and that's when Pip was succeeded by... Yeah, Gary Glazeri and Combs come up, they really replaced those three very nicely.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hugg was a genius at that type of thing, knowing when his ball cup was wearing out and who to keep it.
[SPEAKER_00]: As a matter of fact, I think without a question of a doubt, this is my personal opinion.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, Mr. Murdoch, when
[SPEAKER_00]: When you're talking about any of these things, anything that I talk about or talk to you about, if you took five other ball players and sat them down here, you'd get perhaps five other different opinions, you see?
[SPEAKER_00]: So I am conscious enough that what I tell you or say is only my opinion.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the other fellows may be more correct than I am.
[SPEAKER_00]: How are any of us to know, same as the government today,
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a lot of brains, supposed brains, at the head of the government, and jeez, they're making mistakes all over the place now.
[SPEAKER_00]: One man says one thing, another man says another thing, and they're all smart men.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I'm smart about my business, baseball, but there are other fellows as smart or smarter, and I really don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I tell you from the depths, when I'm real sincere about what I'm saying, which I am all the time, I can't with any veracity prove that I'm right.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it's my positive belief that Huggins was the finest manager that ever lived.
[SPEAKER_00]: We are victims or we're not, I won't say victims, that may be putting the word a little strong, a little cruel, but we certainly are influenced by public relations and publicity and things of that nature that when Stengel
[SPEAKER_00]: with his very colorful personality, also wins a lot of penance, then he becomes one of the greatest managers ever lived.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe McCarthy for a while was considered one of the greatest ever lived, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: And so on and so forth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now they talk about this guy and that guy, but imagine that Huggins lived
[SPEAKER_00]: and not died, and inherited all the ballplayers that Joe McCarthy eventually wound up with, how many pennants do you think Huggins would have won if he had continued on with all those ballplayers that came up there?
[SPEAKER_00]: And the man was a genius, an utter genius in his method of handling, and he had the toughest ballplayers to handle, in my opinion.
[SPEAKER_02]: How could a little guy like Huggins
[SPEAKER_00]: By the backing of Rupert.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a good psychologist.
[SPEAKER_00]: See there's one thing that was infallible.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ruth had to play to hit home runs and Ruth had to play to keep
[SPEAKER_00]: out in front, and if you took him out of the game like when he was suspended and he was having a bad season, then he automatically lowered himself in the estimation of the fans, the public, and everybody else, and consequently it scarred his arguments for money.
[SPEAKER_00]: If anybody needed money, it was Ruth.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the whole war club, you're talking about something that I didn't read the thing by Mose Dale.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a certain, I don't have the vocabulary perhaps to correctly put it in perspective, but there was a feeling or a spirit, or call it what you want.
[SPEAKER_00]: It is more than a spirit.
[SPEAKER_00]: A team spirit is an arousal, in my estimation, a team spirit is an arousal of an additional eagerness and desire for a short period of time.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know what I mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: But a family, your family, my family, we
[SPEAKER_00]: take on a personality or a lifestyle or we live in a pursuit of progression or accomplishment or whatever our philosophy is, we adopt the philosophy as a family and it seems to follow through.
[SPEAKER_00]: That is, I'm not talking about
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm not talking about defectives now, I'm talking about fairly successful families, is this right?
[SPEAKER_00]: If you're talking, well, they talk about human beings, but they talk about animals mostly.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they also talk about human beings as well-bred or breeding.
[SPEAKER_00]: But where does it come from?
[SPEAKER_00]: They say, well, it's bred into them or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, by the same token, the Yankees, this became, started out as a,
[SPEAKER_00]: perhaps as a team spirit, but it developed into a breeding.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when you became a Yankee, you were bred into that type of thing, like crossbred, like two different types of dogs or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you became a Yankee, and that answered a whole lot.
[SPEAKER_00]: You, for some reason, were able to perform a little better.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's just like this letter this guy, that I read you a while ago, wanted to know about the pitching of the 27 Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it said about scoring all those runs.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd think for Christ's sake, to use the language, that they score 10 runs in the first inning every day.
[SPEAKER_00]: A hell of a lot of our games were won in the 8th and 9th innings.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if you didn't start well and didn't pitch well, you weren't in there in the 8th and 9th inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had to pitch well to pitch the game and a lot of games we didn't win until the 8th or 9th inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: We used to call it, the fact of the matter is I coined the expression, what we used to call 5 o'clock lightning.
[SPEAKER_00]: because the game used to start around 3 o'clock, the 8th inning always came up around quarter or 5 or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we used to win a lot of games around that time of the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was called 5 o'clock lightning and that became well known around the league.
[SPEAKER_02]: How many games did you win by in the 27th season?
[SPEAKER_02]: 110.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cleveland won 110, 111, and 54, but they lost four straight in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I mean, how many game margin did you win though?
[SPEAKER_02]: 19.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you still won so many games so close, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, winning by 19 games, you think you must have had a walk away as far as actually winning games.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, a margin of victory in the different game galleys, but apparently it wasn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't really, I would like to see, I would like to see a resume, which I have never seen, and I would like to see a resume.
[SPEAKER_02]: Game by game.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like this book, it's like this maze thing named Wade Hoyt and Ty Cobb.
[SPEAKER_00]: A fellow looked up the
[SPEAKER_00]: I got the thing over here somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh no, it's Pat Harmon down here that wrote the piece.
[SPEAKER_00]: He looked it up, about pitches and their records against certain type hitters.
[SPEAKER_00]: He looked up my record against Cobb, and Cobb hit a 163 against me.
[SPEAKER_00]: in his career, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But don't let that fool you because there are guys like George Burns of Cleveland and Johnny Bassler of Detroit and a few others that wants to hit 500 against me so I'm not taking any credit for Cobb.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you see all these things are open to conjecture, they're open to qualification and ramifications and what I am constantly trying to suggest and preach is the fact that
[SPEAKER_00]: There is so much that whenever a person writes a piece or does a piece, he should qualify it, or should say, as I understand it, or this was given to me, I was given to understand, or I must admit to the fact that I did not participate in this, but
[SPEAKER_00]: The person that did told me this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Everything is open to God.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of the things that I read...
[SPEAKER_02]: I know exactly what you mean because I am a historian and I have to deal with sources and conflicting sources and try to draw some truth from all these things.
[SPEAKER_02]: One thing I've learned is that you should be pretty cautious in any kind of judgments you make, because there's so many qualifying factors.
[SPEAKER_02]: So much of the record just hasn't survived.
[SPEAKER_02]: We don't know what happened in so many things.
[SPEAKER_02]: All we know is it's written down, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it's written by people that don't... Often that's people who hated some people, you know, and you just get one side of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just take, for instance, and please don't misunderstand me, and I don't want anybody ever to misunderstand me.
[SPEAKER_00]: But take the question of Johnny Bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hertzl, who writes for this inquiry here, just says off the top of his head that Johnny Bench is the greatest catcher ever lived.
[SPEAKER_00]: How does he know whether Johnny Bench is the greatest catcher ever lived?
[SPEAKER_00]: Johnny Bench is one of the most agile, clever,
[SPEAKER_00]: accomplished man catcher tagging a man sliding into the home plate or blocking the plate or any of his activities in which a run is being scored or he is obliged to participate in the play at the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: As far as Johnny Bench's receiving the ball from the pitcher is concerned, I can tell you ten catchers better than he.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you understand what I'm talking about?
[SPEAKER_00]: But he hits an opportune home run and stands out for that particular day.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's not as good a hitter as some of these other catchers that hit in the past.
[SPEAKER_00]: But this is supposed to be all-inclusive.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, whenever you talk about people like this,
[SPEAKER_00]: To actually arrive at the truth, all these things must be taken into consideration.
[SPEAKER_00]: And here's a guy named Herzl, the greatest catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never... You take... You'll remember Pavlova... Wasn't it Pavlova?
[SPEAKER_00]: Nazimova or Nazimova, or whatever they call the ballet dancers, remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: you might be nice to move it, don't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: And, well, anyway, or you take, what other stylist can I pick out from the arts?
[SPEAKER_00]: A dancer, Fred Astaire, or some person of ultimate grace and style, is what I'm talking about.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when you get down to that, as a receiving catcher, and a stylist, and where,
[SPEAKER_00]: pass, balls, and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was, to my way of looking at it, there was none better than Ray Shaw.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when you, Ann Cochran is very close, and so is Dickie, and Shang, and Muddy Rule, and Al Lopez, and these different fellows.
[SPEAKER_00]: Probably one of the greatest catches, receding catches from the pitchers that ever lived was Cy Perkins, who had to play second role to Mickey Cochran because he couldn't hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now these fellas don't know about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: If they saw the grace and the handling of these fellas, you couldn't just believe these things.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's like that contest that was held last year in the different major league cities on the most exciting event that ever happened for that team in its history.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I don't think there was, I think there was one event in all of baseball, which happened before 1970,
[SPEAKER_02]: I think I was Johnny Vandermeer's double-no-hitter, but Cleveland, for example, they had something, I think Frank Robbins' opening day home run last year was the greatest event ever happened in Cleveland baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Forgetting Wambi's triple play, and Neil Ball's triple play, and all kinds of other things.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, this home run with the bases loaded.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, this becomes utterly ridiculous.
[SPEAKER_00]: I am very strong in my recommendation on who am I.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wouldn't listen to me for love of money.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm very strong in my recommendation for a line of demarcation between the old and the new.
[SPEAKER_00]: The order should take World War II, 1942, and cut it off there and say anything happened beyond that, before that was old style and old time baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Speaking about the whole, you're a member of the Old Times Committee, and I know the pressure you get from all kinds of people.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is Jackson, Joe Jackson's name ever come up?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he's a black sox, you know, I think they're bored.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're not allowed to... Well, there's no written rule against them.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, but they just automatically, you know, half that ball club would be in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: That Hall of Fame thing is a highly misunderstood.
[SPEAKER_00]: I get it every day.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a sporting news right over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: giving us hell about Ernie Lombardi and something or other, and some of this, that, or some other thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, they can't get through, the average fan can't get through his head that there must be 50 players at this present time, or at least 25, and let's say 30 because that's an even number, who really are qualified for the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we're only allowed to elect two.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, that would take 15 years to get the... Now, in the meanwhile, there are additional names coming out of limbo that are being added to the eligibles for the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: What are we going to do?
[SPEAKER_00]: What are you going to do about it?
[SPEAKER_00]: We run into a situation like this Lindstrom thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why do these fellows, the guy writing in the sporting news said the election of Freddie Lindstrom is utterly ridiculous.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, this fellow doesn't know what he's talking about.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't know balance.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't know style.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't know shift.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't know anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, we don't know anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: This gets you.
[SPEAKER_00]: As Frankie Frisch used to say, doesn't defense count for anything?
[SPEAKER_00]: Defense is one of the best things about the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this isn't what I'm talking about so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went in in 1969.
[SPEAKER_00]: I forget who went in in 68.
[SPEAKER_00]: But nevertheless, there have been about four Yankees that have made it since I went in, starting with me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Myself, Earl Combs, Whitey Ford, Mickey Mantle.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, Barrow was ahead of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody else.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did I say Combs?
[SPEAKER_00]: I did, didn't I?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's all.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's just four.
[SPEAKER_00]: And four in about five years.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's only been six years now since I've been there, or seven, this being the seventh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, there have been almost an equal number of cardinals with Chick Hathie and Enos and Hathie and Jesse Haynes and one or two others.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jan Musial went in with me, you see, and so what you got, you got, and before Lindstrom
[SPEAKER_00]: A couple of years before him, there was Dave Bancroft.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some of the giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and so New York seemed to have a corner on the market, didn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: So people are beginning, and you can't blame them because there are guys around that... Now, on the other hand, I wouldn't ever want to be quoted on this, please.
[SPEAKER_00]: You take Ernie Lombardi.
[SPEAKER_00]: And every round here, we're earning a body's a big, big number.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he did lead the league twice.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had retired with a 3.10 batting average.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Bucky Wallace says he was a great catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: And a couple other guys say he was a great catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Among the general opinion of baseball people, he was a lousy catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Any guy reach out and catch a ball with his bare hand and can't shift.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they don't know what they're talking about.
[SPEAKER_00]: They say, if Ernie Lombardi was a faster man, he would have had a batting average of .350 if he could have beaten Arnett.
[SPEAKER_00]: They don't realize when they say that he was slow, that that's a defect for them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They say that's one of the things that kept them from being what he should be.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Does Joey Sewell come up much?
[SPEAKER_00]: I propose Joey Sewell, and one, and Rick Stevenson also.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I think he is.
[SPEAKER_02]: A couple Alabamans.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joey Sewell has been mentioned.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, he's been on the ballots.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see what they do, so you'll understand.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'll send you around the 1st of December
[SPEAKER_00]: or sooner, a form sheet and it'll have all the list of the eligibles on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe there's 50 or 60 eligibles that have been nominated before, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now you select 10 of those, that group, and you send them in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now that doesn't mean that they are the only ones, that they can't be changed.
[SPEAKER_00]: That doesn't mean you can't cross them out when you get to the meeting.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can delete their name if you want.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that gives them, it's only a guide now.
[SPEAKER_00]: They take those, they boil that down to 10 of the most
[SPEAKER_00]: desirable, or most often mentioned, or who will receive the highest number of mentions.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they will say at the beginning of the meeting that there are these additions that have been suggested, and does anybody wish to comment?
[SPEAKER_00]: And there might be two or three other names added.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you might wind up with 15.
[SPEAKER_00]: people to vote on.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then they pass you the ballots.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, there are only five.
[SPEAKER_00]: You only vote for five.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so you vote for five.
[SPEAKER_00]: In order of preference?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not in the order of preference at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: You just vote for five.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if the two top ones
[SPEAKER_00]: anybody gets a quorum is elected.
[SPEAKER_00]: If nobody gets a quorum the first time, each time they read off the number of votes that they did get, and then they go around a second time, and the bottom ones are eliminated.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they go around the third time.
[SPEAKER_00]: The one difficulty in the thing between you and I is if a couple of them wind up in a tie.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's happened and they have to hold them over for another year.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they've eliminated the rule before this year
[SPEAKER_00]: You could not vote for a manager or an umpire or a league official unless two players were elected.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then you voted for the manager or the umpire or the league official.
[SPEAKER_00]: But with a selection of only two players, you don't have much choice.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, there are plenty of guys that got plenty of votes, like Lombardi himself.
[SPEAKER_00]: I voted for Lombardi, to tell you the truth.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't vote for him this year because the visa was virtually useless.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you have to be at the meeting to have your vote counted?
[SPEAKER_02]: Can your mail ballot count?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is Fred Leib still on the committee?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he get there this time?
[SPEAKER_02]: He did?
[SPEAKER_00]: I read in the paper a couple absentees, but I thought Fred might be one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dan Daniel was sick, and something happened to Terry.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know why Bill Terry wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's not on the committee anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: As a matter of fact, I resigned.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh?
[SPEAKER_02]: After this?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they take it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: They won't pass on it till August the 8th.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: I resigned because of my heart.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got a very bad heart.
[SPEAKER_00]: I damn near went to the hospital up there last year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a kind of a breakdown up there and they were going to knock me off of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I'm not supposed to do much public speaking or anything of that sort.
[SPEAKER_02]: A couple years ago, I made a very detailed study of the great sluggers of the pre-1900 era.
[SPEAKER_02]: I went through all their slugging records and compiled their standing in about seven different categories of hits and different kinds of hits and homers and so on.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then the leaders in this, we found among the top ones there, were not in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's by this point, certainly.
[SPEAKER_02]: But they have been elected since then.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sam Thompson is one of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sam is right at the top of this list.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Roger Conner is another.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's why I'm so happy to see Conner make it this year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you see, we don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's be honest.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lee may know something.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dan Daniel was one guy that knew something about it, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Musial and myself and Terry and Charlie Gerringer, we don't know anything about Sam Thompson.
[SPEAKER_00]: How could you?
[SPEAKER_00]: This is stupid.
[SPEAKER_00]: And really, fellows like Vic Willis and these guys, there should be a meeting of the body of the Hall of Fame
[SPEAKER_00]: governors or whoever controls it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they should go over that all-time list and whomever they think should be qualified or rates that should be in a group taken in or indicated in such a way that they are recognized in the Hall of Fame, whether they are
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's pretty difficult to take a fellow and put him in the Hall of Fame when they bounce the ball and the catcher stood way the hell behind the bat and all this kind of thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And foul, counter the third strike, and all this business.
[SPEAKER_00]: My belief that organized baseball started in 1900 or 1901.
[SPEAKER_00]: There should be a line of demarcation there too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Beyond that, back beyond that, should be old-timers and they should be classified such and they should be a special standard and there should be a special room with these fellows in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: today playing 161 games, 162 games, when you get down to the thing, there's a hell of a lot of difference in what's taking place today and what took place in our day.
[SPEAKER_00]: I very often, I refuse to make comparisons because there's no way to make comparisons.
[SPEAKER_00]: They make a great deal of strikeouts today.
[SPEAKER_00]: Strikeouts didn't mean anything to us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ridiculous.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's a couple of things in your own career I wanted to check on.
[SPEAKER_02]: You came in just about the time the spitball was outlawed.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was outlawed around 1921.
[SPEAKER_02]: Had you thrown it before then?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I never threw the spitball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever think about it before it was outlawed?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, neither did anybody else.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a point, if you're writing anything, make a point of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, why is that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Why would some throw it and a few throw it and others wouldn't?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we didn't think anything of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't think it any better than our curve.
[SPEAKER_01]: That wasn't that effective.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mainly the spitball pitches were effective, but there were a hell of a lot of guys that threw the spitball that weren't effective, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't think that the spitball was unusual.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, we thought the stuff we had was just as good as that.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about other foreign substance, emery?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that was barred when I was in the Army.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dave Danforth and those guys, they did that.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did Danforth do with that ball?
[SPEAKER_02]: He got in all kinds of trouble with Dan Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what he did with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had some kind of a roof.
[SPEAKER_00]: either a rough fingernail or a rough something or other.
[SPEAKER_00]: He roughed up one side of the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Billy Evans saved 13 balls one time against us in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: And those were the balls they sent him to Ben Johnson and the league.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's what cost him his job.
[SPEAKER_00]: Whose job?
[SPEAKER_00]: Danforth.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bill, you haven't saved the ball Danforth was throwing to show how he had scarred it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I can now.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, now you're going overboard.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know whether they scarred it or shined it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now Urban Shocker used to use a spitball pitch, yeah, and he would suck the seams and wet them and suck them and then he
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd get dirt on him, or tobacco, and press them with his finger behind his glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could raise the seam a little bit, see, and all you had to do was raise the seam a little bit and you could make the ball sail like hell.
[SPEAKER_00]: And a lot of these fellas had little tricks that they could employ once in a while if you could catch them at it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dan Forth was supposed to pitch against Waller Johnson in an exhibition game after the season was over in Baltimore at one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was two all-star teams, like George Sissel played first base, Eddie Collins second base, and the one around there, that caliber of player playing, and the two teams of that nature going to play each other for some charity.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Johnson was going to pitch against Dan Forth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Johnson went over to the other ball club and said, look, he said, I'm going to have to tell you, Johnson was a very quiet fellow, went over and said, look, he said, I'm going to have to tell you fellows that you better be a little bit loose up at the plate because if any of those balls sail and anybody gets hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: By Danforth?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, by Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the balls would, if they,
[SPEAKER_00]: You see that they were hung over until the next inning and Johnson pitched them as fast as he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: If he hit anybody, it's not going to be my fault.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had a lot of... Johnson, I guess, never went backwards, not to throw at people.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was a very... Did you bat against him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did you like to bat against Walter Johnson?
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't do much batting against him.
[SPEAKER_00]: We just stood there.
[SPEAKER_00]: At least I did.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever hit him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or hit the ball?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, hit the ball, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I never got any hits on him, I recall.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was wicked.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was wicked in the way he pitched sidearm.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd like to see him pitching today.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wow.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was probably the fastest pitcher you've ever seen.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, in my opinion, the fastest I've ever pitched.
[SPEAKER_00]: These fellas don't know why.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had probably pretty good control.
[SPEAKER_00]: They take a fellow like, now this is a boast, and I admit it's a boast.
[SPEAKER_00]: People, if they ever heard this or people do hear it, can make little of it if they want to.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I'm telling you, and I'm not boasting, I mean I'm not being...
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm a smart aleck when I say this, but I was fast myself, and I believe I was as fast as Seaver easily.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I never struck out anybody, three a game, I think my average, something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that was neither here nor there.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had on the 23 staff like Jones and Bush and Shockey and Mays, and Pennock wasn't fast,
[SPEAKER_00]: But we had fellows on that staff, all of them could throw as fast as I could.
[SPEAKER_00]: So there wasn't this business about being fast.
[SPEAKER_00]: When we hear these fellows talk today about Nolan Ryan and
[SPEAKER_00]: and Tom Seaver and these different guys, and Bob Gibson.
[SPEAKER_00]: What the hell?
[SPEAKER_00]: We had three and four guys in one club with that fast.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, we were, in those days, it was a different type of pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was fastball and curb, although they did throw knuckleballs and they did throw forkballs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe Bush threw the forkball.
[SPEAKER_00]: It always makes me laugh when you hear Williams and DiMaggio and these fellas talk and say that the pitchers didn't
[SPEAKER_00]: only had fastballs and curves.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hell, we had more stuff and different kinds of stuff than these fellas have today.
[SPEAKER_00]: And on our ball club alone, I threw the palm ball, I'll show you a picture of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: The palm ball, a three-quarter speed ball, the fastball, and the curve ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the curve ball wasn't too good, I must admit.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Joe Bush threw the fourth ball, Sam Jones threw a fadeaway and a curveball, Schalke threw two curves, and he's fastballing a change of pace.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pennock had the overhand curve, the sidearm curve, and one of the best screwballs in the business.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as I told you, and Shocker threw the spitball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And where the hell are they?
[SPEAKER_00]: And when you get down to it, what are they talking about?
[SPEAKER_00]: I threw the slider toward the end of my career, and the slider is nothing new.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, George Yulee invented the slider in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if you ask these fellas today who George Yulee was, none of them know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I talked to George Yulee in a real nice interview.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had arm trouble every other year, it seemed like.
[SPEAKER_02]: But didn't your arm get tired?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever have arm trouble?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yes, but not from throwing or pitching in a game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got arm trouble from throwing
[SPEAKER_00]: 10 cent balls that had milk bottles in them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had one night in Philadelphia out at Bob, when Bob Carpenter, the owner of the Phillies, was just a little boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Pennock took Babe and myself and Dugan out to this street fair out in Kennett Square.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where Pennock lived.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and well, that's where the Carpenters lived, too, out there, near there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this was for Bob Carpenter's street fair out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we stood off and threw these balls at this paper mache milk bottles, and I hurt my arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: and swelled way up when I was out for six weeks, five weeks in 1926, and I might have won some more games.
[SPEAKER_02]: What do you think caused it?
[SPEAKER_02]: An unnatural motion?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, a ten-cent ball and not a big shoe or something up near my elbow.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did Huggins say about that?
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He thought I hurt it in the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't disabuse him.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, but they...
[SPEAKER_02]: I would think throwing a fastball pitcher, throwing it all so much, would begin to take some toll, but apparently... Fastball pitcher, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't, unless you twist your arm, throwing a fastball.
[SPEAKER_00]: A fastball should be thrown, is released away from you, out from you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Your arm comes forward,
[SPEAKER_00]: and the ball is released as far as your step almost.
[SPEAKER_00]: before you let the ball go.
[SPEAKER_00]: A curveball, the elbow is brought in toward the side.
[SPEAKER_00]: You pull it down, you pull your elbow down in toward your side and snap your wrist as you release it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Really fastball pitchers are less likely to have... That's right, much less likely to have arm trouble than a curveball pitcher or a screwball pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it amazes me, it amazes me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I say these things not as, please don't misunderstand, I say these things not as for personal aggrandizement in the image sense, but in 1936, when I was down there through, I think it was 36,
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in Montclair.
[SPEAKER_00]: Montclair, New Jersey was my home at the time, and Pittsburgh happened to be playing in Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was taken with appendicitis and carted off to the hospital and operated on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Within four weeks, I finished a game in Chicago, and three days after pitching in Chicago for the workout, I pitched a 15-inning ball game against Freddie Fitzsimmons, and he beat me 2-1 in Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, we had the bases loaded in the ninth inning with no one out and didn't score, and he beat me 2-1 in the 15th inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: These guys today, they find it hard to pitch five or six innings.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, why?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Look for me to the answer, because these are the things that I refuse to make comparisons, because I do not know why these things are taking place today.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're either not trained to pitch these innings, or their philosophy is entirely different, because they are following the philosophy of the young people of the world today, or they're following the philosophy of labor.
[SPEAKER_00]: and doing specialization jobs or just with time limits or being paid like a form of piecework or some damn thing, but it's not the philosophy that was used by the players of my day and
[SPEAKER_00]: nor the work schedules and philosophies of your father or my father who poured in a full day and used to come struggling home and get up and go back to work the next day.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now a lot of these fellows that work in factories get up and they go to work and they do the same thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: They come home and they do whatever they do and they go back and work in the factory again.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they're getting so many fringe benefits and so much time off, their working conditions are entirely different.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the comparisons are a little bit stupid, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: When you came up with the Red Sox, and even after you were over the Yankees, did any of the older players or pitchers or coaches give you any help?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were on your own.
[SPEAKER_00]: The only fellow that ever helped me was Herb Pennock.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was just a matter of personal friendship.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why I laugh at this Carl Mays thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: The only guy that ever helped me was Pennock.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a long conversation on the train one night and he explained what he thought I was doing wrong and it was a matter of pitching routine and to the point where the next year I developed almost a catechism about pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: It worked.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was more corrective in judgment.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was another thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: We talked about pitching and playing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't tell you.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, now I was about to make a statement, and I was about to make a statement which would be
[SPEAKER_00]: But you couldn't vouch for its veracity because I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm not around these fellas.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I don't travel with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm not in their conversations.
[SPEAKER_00]: So how would I know?
[SPEAKER_00]: It doesn't strike me.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's an impression of mine.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's put it this way.
[SPEAKER_00]: That they don't talk about pitching the way or playing the way we did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe Morgan does.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Reds and Rose does.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I broadcast for the Reds for 25 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I have yet to have any baseball player, pitcher, or otherwise ask me one single question on how to do anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, that's a true.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's a truism.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I would the older players
[SPEAKER_02]: look on you as somebody going to take their job away and not want to help you out?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is this a job competition?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, that's a fallacy.
[SPEAKER_02]: They just didn't care about you when you came up?
[SPEAKER_00]: What, you mean in a book?
[SPEAKER_02]: As a younger player, needing help and guidance, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did they make it hard for you?
[SPEAKER_00]: When I came to the Giants in 1916, the regular players
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that was their general disposition of the entire league then, which changed.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they didn't, there wasn't any way to make it tough except they tried, when I was pitching batting practice, they amused themselves with trying to hit me with the ball and that sort of thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they, no, they weren't mean to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were very nice in a way, Larry Doyle especially.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were some pretty rugged guys, Benny Kalf and Art Fletcher and a few of them, and of course Herzog.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Herzog and Heine Zimmerman didn't talk to each other.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you know Zimmerman at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, not well.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got barred.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was a different set of men.
[SPEAKER_00]: The men changed during the years.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did you generally get on with umpires?
[SPEAKER_02]: Fine.
[SPEAKER_02]: What happened to Brick Owens that day?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, Brick... ...during the years.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did you generally get on with umpires?
[SPEAKER_02]: Fine.
[SPEAKER_02]: What happened to Brick Owens that day?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Brick Owens is still wrong and I'm still right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Couldn't be.
[SPEAKER_00]: He couldn't be right because he was behind the play to begin with.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember the inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was the last inning in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: somebody single to score the tying run, and there was a runner on second base who tried to score two, and the throw was from the outfield.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, on first base I guess it was, and somebody on first base who went to third, and the throw in from the outfield went by Wally Shang, the catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was behind the plate, one thing or another, and I ran to the plate,
[SPEAKER_00]: God be my witness and judge, I flopped on the plate with my whole body covering the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Shang threw me the ball, and this guy, I think it was Barrett, if I'm not mistaken, slid into the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he slid around me, and then he tried to reach back with his hand and reach under me and tag the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I grabbed his wrist.
[SPEAKER_00]: and held his wrist and put the ball on his hand.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was the ball on his hand, and it's a good six inches away from the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he couldn't be missed in any manner, shape, or form.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Owens said he was safe.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that beat me.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I jumped up and took a punch at Owens.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could have whipped me without anything on me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I took a punch at him with his chest protector, his mask, and everything else on.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you can see.
[SPEAKER_02]: You really swung at him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, uh, that shows you how stupid I am.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, uh, and anyway, that's when I was suspended for those days.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I got along well with the umpires.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nalin and Dineen and Jack O'Conlon is one of my best friends.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, uh,
[SPEAKER_02]: Everybody says Bill McGowan was a great umpire.
[SPEAKER_02]: Good umpire, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Billy Evans?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, the best.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever know an umpire named Ollie Chill?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he's the guy that missed the third strike on me that cost me the last game of the 1921 World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, damn right.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was right through the center of the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right through the center of the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why didn't you take a punch at him?
[SPEAKER_00]: I jumped about three feet in the air, and
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the fourth ball, I think, Ross to Frankie Frisch.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hold the phone.
[SPEAKER_00]: That might have been Ross Youngs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think Frisch had put Frisch on second.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they hit the ball to Peckenpah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Peck let the ball go through his legs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it rolled about five feet in the outfield.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he couldn't find the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He kept turning around, looking for the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Frisch scored all the way from second.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think Ben Johnson fired him about twice.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he fired him once, I think, about 1917.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was surprised to see him back in the league later on.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I'm playing a World Series game.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't quite figure that one out.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was, I think, indicted for murder one
[SPEAKER_02]: up in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, somebody, somebody, they used to, and I didn't know the meaning of it, because I was a kid then, and I didn't know what it meant, but the older players used to yell out, what time is it by whoever the fellow, some other umpire's watch?
[SPEAKER_00]: Intimating that he stole a watch from some guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Referring to Chill?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And what time is it by so-and-so's watch?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a good story.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I don't know whether that's true or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: They say so damn many other things.
[SPEAKER_02]: You think, on the whole, the umpires are really dedicated?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's a tough, rugged job.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're a group of men to be admired, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: I am very, very sad to believe, to know, and to realize that their names are not included
[SPEAKER_00]: box scores anymore, you know, and that they don't mention them, and they don't get enough publicity.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the umpires, you know, that old kill the umpire thing, and the end of the ball player versus the umpire, you know, it was a source of entertainment to the fans, and they deprived the fans.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe the umpires don't want it, I don't know, but I think that the lack of recognition of these fellas is deplorable.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever pitch in a game with just one umpire?
[SPEAKER_02]: Or was there always two by the time you came along?
[SPEAKER_02]: Always two.
[SPEAKER_02]: He used to have just one, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He used to cut bases on him and everything else, and he couldn't see everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's why they picked on him so much.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd miss some things, and how could he help it when he was the only one trying to watch the whole game?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, there were always two.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what they were supposed to be.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they do a good job, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, it's ridiculous in a way to ask people, like, what do you think of the home plate in the World Series?
[SPEAKER_00]: How do I know?
[SPEAKER_00]: I saw it on television, I saw the replay, and I still can't tell you what happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know whether the guy, whether he shoved, what's his name, the catcher, whether he shoved him or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: He claims he did, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the umpire, you'll have to leave that to the umpire.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think I read somewhere here where you thought that you were leading the Yankees kind of hurt.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Hurt me?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Huggins had deceased, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Schottky manager then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that part of the problem?
[SPEAKER_02]: Having a teammate managing so soon after?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was mainly my fault.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was going through some domestic trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the 1929 season,
[SPEAKER_00]: Schalke and I didn't get along in spring training that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had some problems with each other.
[SPEAKER_00]: Although I don't think Schalke perhaps had that much to do with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He may have, but I think Ed Barrow may have had more problems.
[SPEAKER_00]: I would imagine Barrows had something to do with it, but they...
[SPEAKER_00]: I think if Huggins had remained, hadn't died, I would never have been away from the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it hurt me, yes, when I went to other ball clubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: They weren't run the same, they were more like corner lot teams.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, I believe, it's my belief,
[SPEAKER_00]: that I am in an enviable position, and not of my own doing or not of my own manufacture, of being able to say that I was with or probably played with an organization whose
[SPEAKER_00]: as I mentioned before, philosophy and practices in the approach to the actual playing of the game was so far superior to anything that these players know today.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not today, I mean afterwards, after the old Yankees died.
[SPEAKER_00]: to describe it to these fellows, they couldn't believe it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wouldn't believe it to begin with, and they'd think you were boasting, and they'd think you were telling lies, or they'd think that you were laying it on, that I get a little tired of people telling me that because you get old, that time colors your imagination, and that you believe these things.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I tell you that it was run like a primary school class in primary school,
[SPEAKER_00]: When you sat on the bench and you weren't allowed to talk about anything else but baseball or yell at the other club, that's the way it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was the discipline at its highest, believe me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when I got away from there, then I found out why we beat those other clubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's the same as I see some loose organizations as I have seen.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I would say to some of the fellows, yeah, I understand.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why we beat you.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's because you're not devoted to it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're not dedicated.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're not devoted to purpose.
[SPEAKER_00]: It isn't a matter of dedication.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a matter of realization.
[SPEAKER_00]: A dedicated player is, a dedicated man or a dedicated player, that's an inborn, it's an inborn desire.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's something that wells up, that it's a natural, it's a natural motivation, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: The other is, that I'm talking about, is sort of a manufactured thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: You become inoculated or revved up because of something that... Who was responsible for this?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it Rupert, Barrow, Huggins?
[SPEAKER_00]: And Barrow, and Huggins.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the players themselves.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got to believing in themselves, and I think Ruth was a great...
[SPEAKER_02]: The most undisciplined of them all was...
[SPEAKER_00]: An example... Oh, well this is...
[SPEAKER_00]: He's undisciplined.
[SPEAKER_00]: I have nothing to do with you.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're off the track, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ruth was more disciplined than people believed.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Ruth was... Ruth, that's where the mistakes are made.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ruth was very conscious of the world.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ruth was very conscious of... was taught to be very conscious of fandom.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ruth was very warm with the public and very conscious of the public.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he...
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a perfectionist on the ball field.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he a leader then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, not a leader.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't holler, come on, hit, hooray, let's go, or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what you're talking about.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he wasn't that kind of leader, but he was a guy that he believed in his baseball performance was so good that
[SPEAKER_00]: the other fellows that tried to be good along with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a privilege to play with them and of course the money was good and all this sort of thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know they always talk about, I've heard of comments about Frank McCormick.
[SPEAKER_00]: They said that if he had had Chick Hafey on the same ball club with him at one time or
[SPEAKER_00]: and had somebody that could out-hit him by 10 points or 15 points, Frank would have hit 10 points higher himself, but Frank was too satisfied.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see what I mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: And these are the things that...
[SPEAKER_02]: There's a story in here, I think it may have been at the time Huggins died,
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Hauser hit a home run on you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you got taken out?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They said that they couldn't do after 30 what you did before.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was correct.
[SPEAKER_00]: Huggins, that's why he was what he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a great student of individual psychology.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the first man that I ever heard say, I've heard it said a lot since,
[SPEAKER_00]: But you see up until a certain period of time, there was a sort of a general sports philosophy
[SPEAKER_00]: The team is the thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: We do the team, the teamwork, you know, and all the business and that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't belong, he doesn't fit in well.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, the Huggins felt the same way about some fellows that played in the team.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you the story in a minute.
[SPEAKER_00]: But on the other hand, I'll take nine Ty Cobbs and preference all the teamwork you can put together if you want to know the truth.
[SPEAKER_00]: 10 or 9 Beiruts, the hell with the teamwork.
[SPEAKER_00]: The point being that Huggins was one of the first men that I ever heard say that you couldn't manage.
[SPEAKER_00]: 25 men all the same.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rules didn't apply to 25 men.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't bind 25 men with the same rules.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could try it, put it there and try it, but don't expect it to work to perfection.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had to manage each guy differently, which he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know how he did it, but he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bob Musil was fined many times in his life by the league for some altercation with some umpire doing something, but he'd never pay a fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wouldn't put on his uniform.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're supposed to pay the fine before you go out on the field on a certain date, you know?
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the fine has to be paid by personal check.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Musil just wouldn't put on a uniform.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just said that no, he wouldn't submit to a fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: He laid off a couple of days, or a day, and Huggins would call him in the office.
[SPEAKER_00]: Musil wouldn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's very quiet, Musil.
[SPEAKER_00]: He hardly spoke a word, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come back out of the office, sit on the chair.
[SPEAKER_00]: and not say a word to anybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I don't know how they fixed it up, but they did it fixed up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's an example of Huggins had to manage him.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were a lot of incidents that took place in that ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it was a pleasure to play for.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you, they had a supreme confidence in themselves.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think Joe McCarthy was a tremendous manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he was almost the equivalent of Huggins.
[SPEAKER_00]: In his little specialties and his devices and manners of play, I think McCarthy was...
[SPEAKER_00]: I never played for him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I talked to him last spring up at his home there.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was about a day before J.D.'
[SPEAKER_02]: 's eighth birthday.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was very nice to talk to.
[SPEAKER_01]: You played on with how many teams here after then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Who managed over Detroit?
[SPEAKER_02]: Bucky Harris when you were there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then... Then I went to the A's.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Connie Mack.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wasn't there too long, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: The funny thing over there in Philadelphia, I won ten and lost three for that club over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I was fat and out of shape.
[SPEAKER_00]: And at the end of the year or the next year they sent me a contract, believe it or not, Connie Mack sent me a contract with a $2,500 cut.
[SPEAKER_00]: after I had won 10 and lost 3 for him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I wasn't in condition when I went there.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he didn't have to relieve me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, relieve me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, I pitched my four games as well.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I went down to spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: And during the winter, I got in shape.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went down from 206 pounds to 170.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when I went down to see him in Fort Myers, he said, I'll give you the money.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he restored the original salary.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, I've already talked to Brooklyn and Brooklyn, and I'll have to see what they want to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Brooklyn offered me this bonus, so I went to Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I wasn't successful there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was still having troubles.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I kind of loused up my career right around that time in my life.
[SPEAKER_02]: You went over to the Pirates in 33.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was Jewel Enzo in them?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: George Gibson.
[SPEAKER_02]: Had a real good year in 34.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't start the games until the 4th of July.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I won 12 of those games on the 4th of July.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, that was a good year.
[SPEAKER_02]: 191 innings.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was managing that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Trainer.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know why, I can't understand, there are very many things I can't answer for you, and there were no reason for them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was just married in 33 over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then in 35,
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched against Cincinnati and won the opening game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I beat Cincinnati here in the opening game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we went from here to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was a, jeez, I'll never forget that day.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I pitched in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we were leading 8-2, 7-2 or 8-2.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were leading, I forget the score, we were leading by quite a considerable score.
[SPEAKER_00]: And a fight broke out, that was it.
[SPEAKER_00]: A fight broke out between Guy Bush, who was then traded to Pittsburgh,
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if it was Charlie Grimm or whoever it was managing the Cubs, or somebody on the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they held the game up 40 minutes, and it must have been 40 degrees out, or 35, or 39, or what it called there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I sat on the bench there for about 35 minutes without throwing a ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a long inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we went out and started the next inning, and I got the first guy out, and the next guy singled, and the next guy hit a ball at Tommy Thevenin playing second base, and he booted the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think I walked the next guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we were all leading about eight to two.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they took me out, and they took me out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, pardon me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I won the opening game against Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went to St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, we went back to Pittsburgh, that was it, and opened the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I pitched the opening game of the season against the St. Louis Cardinals, and they beat me three to two over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we went to Chicago, and the...
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm getting this mixed up somewhere now.
[SPEAKER_00]: At any rate, they put in a guy named Jack Salverson,
[SPEAKER_00]: And the trainer left him in there while he walked six straight men.
[SPEAKER_00]: And goddamn it, the Cubs didn't score, I think, nine or ten runs in the inning, and they beat us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I didn't lose the game, but that's... Then I didn't pitch again.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't start me again for...
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't start again, I don't know when.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I can't understand why to this day.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think the cold weather kind of hit, but catching up to that cold weather didn't do me any good because I wasn't a youngster then.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then things started to go a little haywire.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was through.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know what happens to you when you start when you're 15 years old?
[SPEAKER_00]: at 16 years old, it isn't a question of being tired physically, it's of being tired.
[SPEAKER_00]: You become sated with the game and the experiences and you kind of wish that you had a change of... How did you get into broadcasting?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I started on a show called Grandstand and Bandstand, which was a
[SPEAKER_00]: a show sponsored by Wheaties.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a show, it was a guest show, but it had a 39-piece band, 35-piece band.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, but they had, I used to do three
[SPEAKER_00]: bits in the show, went for three hours, three and a half hours or something in the afternoons.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was in New York?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, WMCA.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had, oh God, they had football players, actresses, actors, they had everybody on that program.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you volunteer?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they ask you to come?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no, no, I got paid, I was a regular, but they would get people in like Mae Murray, or they get the
[SPEAKER_00]: People coming off the boats, they'd send them down and get interviews with people coming from Europe.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they'd get, oh hell, we had... You interviewed them, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Sims, they had bridge players, and Culbertson, and yeah, oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was quite a program.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, did you plan to do this eventually?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did this just kind of happen?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I knew a fellow in the show business in New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: He thought it was good for me to get in the radio, but there was a struggle there for quite a while, for a few years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Struggle when I came out here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I came out here in January 1942.
[SPEAKER_00]: What the hell, the war started.
[SPEAKER_00]: 1942, the first year I came here, the first year of the war.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody was thinking about baseball, they were thinking about the war.
[SPEAKER_02]: I thought you met a struggle in becoming an announcer, perfecting a technique.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they wouldn't give me an audition in New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: They said ballplayers didn't have any vocabulary, so they wouldn't let me audition for the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you the first ballplayer announcer?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I think Gabby Streep was the first, I think Jack Greeney and Cleveland, and Harry Harman and Detroit, and myself, I believe.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where did you make your home during your baseball career, your off-season home?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, we traveled a great deal.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went to Florida, Miami.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you work much in off-season?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, we traveled.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were in Miami and Coast and lived in Honolulu one winter.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we, that was the first five years I was married to this girl, since 1933 on.
[SPEAKER_02]: That story you tell about
[SPEAKER_02]: Your wife been up in the seats?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, she was in this one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: I forgot exactly now what it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was she missing at one time?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did she leave her seat and you were looking up to her?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, she had her feet up on the chair reading a newspaper.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kind of nervous, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, she didn't know anything about baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was quite a...
[SPEAKER_00]: Say, I'm going to do something for you if you will return it and send it to me if you'd like it.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you'd like to use it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wait till I see what I can get.
[SPEAKER_00]: See if I got it.
[SPEAKER_02]: We've just been looking over some of Wade Hoyt's pictures.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a great collection.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's autographing some copies now, which he's giving me, and I'm going to
[SPEAKER_02]: Ask a few more questions here.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see in this article in the Sporting News, it must have been the month you started in with the broadcasting for the Reds here.
[SPEAKER_02]: He refers to Will Wedge of the New York Sun on the label on you, the aristocrat of baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it's a very nice label.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've been called almost everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: That struck me as very appropriate from what I've seen and read about you.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you hear it very often?
[SPEAKER_02]: Are you familiar with that term?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, somewhat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who did he say?
[SPEAKER_00]: Will Wedge called it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, the New York Sun.
[SPEAKER_01]: And also, if you'll pardon me,
[SPEAKER_01]: He just died, the communist for the New York Times.
[SPEAKER_01]: Daly?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Arthur Daly.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good friend of mine, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got to be a friend of those fellas to have them call you that.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had good relations with the press then, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Very, very, very good relations, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Always.
[SPEAKER_01]: Frankie Graham was one of my finest friends, Frankie Graham.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wrote the history of the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you read that?
[SPEAKER_00]: The old history, I wrote part of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: You what?
[SPEAKER_01]: I wrote part of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it came out in the 40s?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it came out the year that we came here.
[SPEAKER_00]: As a matter of fact, I finished my part of it the night before I came to Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Are you given proper credit?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, not so much, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't bother, but it's verbatim in there from
[SPEAKER_01]: from the time I joined the Yankees until 1930.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: And to tell you the truth, Frankie Graham was such a lovely fellow that he didn't owe me 10 cents.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you know that he saw that
[SPEAKER_01]: that they sent me commissions for over five years, I collected all that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he, I knew Frankie since you see, I knew Frankie Graham since I was a kid.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that's how, and also Tom Meaney.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was going to ask you about Tom Meaney.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, and all those folks, Tommy Holmes, John Drebbinger, John Drebbinger, and Daniel, of course.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then Daniel and Bill McGeehan and, what's his name, a great friend of mine who went to the
[SPEAKER_01]: became one of the officials of the Giants.
[SPEAKER_01]: Schumacher?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or Patterson?
[SPEAKER_01]: Gary Schumacher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I knew them all.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had good relations with them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I want to tell you something while I'm speaking of the press of those days.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were doing prohibition those days.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't unusual for the phone to ring after practice or after a game and have somebody call up and say, hey, you got anything to drink up there?
[SPEAKER_01]: And it would be one of the newspaper men.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'd say, no, come on up.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we'd sit around up there perhaps and talk.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know that never was there ever a confidence violated.
[SPEAKER_01]: They'd sit around and we'd talk with them.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can't do that today.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can remember one, I'm not going to mention any names, but one of our most prominent writers in New York, I was on a plane with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: going from New York to Detroit a few years ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was in an intimate conversation with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had a very nice time together.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I thought, until I read his
[SPEAKER_01]: until I read his column in one of the syndicated column in the paper, which he had distorted the whole, everything that I had said.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's one of my favorite hates today.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't understand these kind of fellows, and then a couple of fellows that are always criticizing the old-timers committee that want to know why so-and-so was elected.
[SPEAKER_01]: You see, they do strange things.
[SPEAKER_01]: They rushed in after we elected George Kelly of the Giants as the first baseman, and they
[SPEAKER_01]: wanted to know why we elected George Kelly.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, George Kelly wasn't the greatest homerun hitter in the world, among a number of other things, and it seems today that everybody's guided by the homerun, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I happen to say... Gee, this pen doesn't work very well.
[SPEAKER_01]: I happen to say that
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he was a remarkable ball player and McGraw used him for things that you don't see nowadays.
[SPEAKER_01]: For instance, he was one of the fellas that went into the outfield behind second base and took the throws from the outfield as a relay to the home plate, which you don't see in the present day.
[SPEAKER_01]: You see what I mean?
[SPEAKER_01]: wrote the story, and the story appeared in the paper that he was elected, that I said that he was elected because he took the throws from the outfield and threw to the home plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: George Kelly was an instrument of defense that seconded none.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they just leave out that part.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, I can't tell you.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's been some enmity.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is Bob Roeg on there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nice guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: But there's been some enmity between the regular writers and ourselves on that stuff, the old-timers committee.
[SPEAKER_01]: You see, those fellas just don't understand.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you think there's a difference in writers today than in the past, as far as, well, you mentioned the one not involved in Congress, but in the reporting of the game, in their knowledge of the game, do they know baseball the way they used to?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: They go to the fifth inning and leave at the seventh, I understand, sometimes.
[SPEAKER_02]: They don't write the game stories much.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, you can't read an account of a game and find out what happened.
[SPEAKER_02]: You read what the interview is in the locker room after the game.
[SPEAKER_02]: The old-time games, the game accounts were exciting stories to read.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I tell you, we must be fair.
[SPEAKER_01]: You see, they're having problems today, I imagine, because there are so many other sports that have jumped into prominence and have elevated themselves to the same plateau as baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they are asked to cover these sports
[SPEAKER_02]: They're the products of a generation in which baseball is not the number one sport.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's part of the reflection.
[SPEAKER_02]: They don't have an interest or concern in it now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, don't you think that everybody today, including writers,
[SPEAKER_00]: are seeking, I won't say the easy way out, but they're filled with, not trickery, but I don't know what it is, some kind of a get the job done, this is good enough, you know, one of those kind of things.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the way I feel.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, some of the ballplayers are the same way.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess humanity's all the same, and I guess you and I are the same, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: We don't happen to think of it, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Perhaps we're just as guilty of what we're criticizing others for as ourselves.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I always did like the press.
[SPEAKER_01]: The press always was good with me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I have a question, you're probably sick and tired of hearing it, but it's a kind of traditional one about the biggest thrill.
[SPEAKER_02]: Does anything stand out at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, there were four thrills, really.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is what I write to people.
[SPEAKER_01]: The first one was, of course, signing when I was 15 years old.
[SPEAKER_01]: There could be nothing, because you must understand, Gene, that
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Governor Rhodes, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that in those days, a kid was seen and not heard.
[SPEAKER_01]: You see, he didn't have the free license to speak.
[SPEAKER_00]: And his father used to say, when we want to hear from you, we'll ask you.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that kind of thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: And children are seen and not heard.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so consequently, when I signed when I was 15 years old, that became something of a national sensation, you see, because a kid
[SPEAKER_01]: signed at the age of 15, and that was, gee, practically unheard of.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kids had to be in early at night, and they weren't allowed here and there and that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the second one was the first game against Detroit, and beating them 2 to 1 in 12 innings, and had an incident with Cobb and all that sort of thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you must recall, too,
[SPEAKER_01]: that I didn't have the money to wire my father or telephone or didn't know enough to send a telegram or anything of that nature.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I didn't
[SPEAKER_01]: I just walked on air, and he, the poor man at home, he could see that I had started the game, but he didn't know how it turned out, because he only got it about on the first page when they used to have those line scores, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: When did he find out?
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a call with the New York Journal later that evening to find out that I'd won the game, see what I mean?
[SPEAKER_01]: But that was a big thrill.
[SPEAKER_01]: The 21 World Series?
[SPEAKER_02]: Lit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, and then the next one was the 21 World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, of course, that was the Supreme.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was the story in that last game, the one you lost again?
[SPEAKER_02]: Or was that the last game?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, they got a single and I walked.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought I had, I think it was Ross Young struck out, but he took a base on balls that put two on and two out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then somebody hit a ball to Peckinpah and the ball went through Peck's legs.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then the Hall of Fame was the next one.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can't make up my mind.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which was the more exciting moment, the actual induction or the moment I was notified?
[SPEAKER_00]: Because the moment I was notified was coming off the 18th tee.
[SPEAKER_01]: I suspect that probably was it.
[SPEAKER_01]: at the Belair Country Club down there, the W. Biltmore.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the caddy man said, hey, wait, you're wanted on long-distance phone.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, who's calling?
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, Dayton, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dayton, Ohio?
[SPEAKER_00]: Who the hell in Dayton, Ohio?
[SPEAKER_00]: What do they want me for?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I answered the phone.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was Ritter Collette.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Ritter said, congratulations.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, on what?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, being elected to the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, come on, Ritt, you're kidding.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, that's true.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, oh, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: RIT, please, please don't start.
[SPEAKER_01]: What do you want?"
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, please don't start any practical jokes because this is not a good time for practical jokes.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, especially about a thing like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, no, I'm not kidding you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now all of a sudden I realized it was true and it broke me up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't talk to her no longer.
[SPEAKER_01]: I started to quiver and started to cry.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, Rit, I'll have to call you back in about an hour.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'll answer all the questions you want then.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I said, I can't talk to you any longer now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I really can't.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I could hardly talk.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm talking to you better than I talk to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the two, well, I have about five pros down at this place.
[SPEAKER_01]: One of them went in the next room in the bar in the cocktail lounge and made this announcement.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when I walked in,
[SPEAKER_01]: all stood up and gave me a standing ovation.
[SPEAKER_01]: And of course, I guess that's pretty hard to beat that moment.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was the first realization that I was in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: And although the actual induction was a complete thrill in itself and something that can never occur again, nevertheless,
[SPEAKER_00]: Nevertheless, it was a wonderful thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: So what anybody asks me, I have a little difficult time telling them which is which.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've had a pretty complete life insofar as that type of thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I forgot I was on the air.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you turn it off in time?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wait a minute.
[SPEAKER_02]: The Saturday Post article I asked him about.
[SPEAKER_01]: All right.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came to me in Montclair with the finished article.
[SPEAKER_01]: You understand?
[SPEAKER_01]: I told him, Stanley, that cannot go in the magazine the way it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: The last 600 to 800 words, you'll have to revise.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because this is knocking the National League, and I'm playing in the National League.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a day I was supposed to be heading for spring training with the Brooklyn Dodgers.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, you can't print it that way, Stanley.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I don't want it that way.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'm very, very bitter about this.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is one of the most bitter things in my baseball history.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, all right, I'll change that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, you've got to sweeten it because I don't believe that's the way you've written it at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: And by George, he never changed a word of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not one word of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, Tom Meany had written a piece called Why the American League Wins.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, he wrote a piece called
[SPEAKER_01]: The new minor league, the national.
[SPEAKER_01]: That appeared the week before mine.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mine was called, Why the American League Wins.
[SPEAKER_01]: My piece was designed to just the same as you would talk to me about the difference between the bridge system of Sims and Culbertson.
[SPEAKER_01]: You understand?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was talking to him or tried to talk to him about the difference between the systems of the American and National League.
[SPEAKER_01]: For instance, the National League pitched low because they wanted you to hit the ball on the ground for the double play.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember the story of the article, the piece that I said that you pitch load Ruth and Gehrig and they hit home runs off you.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is nuts.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'm giving you a quick example.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sid Keener or somebody who wrote a book or something and it was almost devoted to me, I guess, and told what a clown I was.
[SPEAKER_01]: to talk like that, that I was just offering some stupid suggestion and ridiculed me all through the book, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And because Stanley Frank let the thing go, let the piece ride.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I never said those things that he wrote.
[SPEAKER_01]: what I did say were qualified and were of a different connotation than he implied, you see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And where do I wind up?
[SPEAKER_01]: When I went to pitch in St. Louis, they wrote a piece in the St. Louis, some guy wrote a piece in the St. Louis paper said, Wade Hoyt, the guy who called the National League the Minor League, that was Meany's piece, is going to pitch today.
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Frank's piece?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, he said...
[SPEAKER_01]: Mean he said that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Mean he said, the title of his piece was The New Minor League, The National.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that implied that I, then in the St. Louis Post or whatever, Dispatch or whatever it was, he said that I said that they called the National League a Minor League, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And, uh, uh, that was not, that was uh, that was uh,
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, that left me bitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: That left me bitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And by the way, I see it in one item here quickly.
[SPEAKER_00]: It says, Hoyt picks his all-star team.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this was in his tale of Spring Peach back in 1942.
[SPEAKER_00]: I would no longer pick an all-star team.
[SPEAKER_00]: There are too many great players.
[SPEAKER_01]: There are too many players with a marginal difference to pick any all-star team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anybody that picks an all-time team
[SPEAKER_01]: It was crazy.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was only one ball player, in my estimation, that was the greatest of them all, and it was Rue.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I don't hold with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Picking some guy right there wants me to...
[SPEAKER_01]: pick an all-star team.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I say right there, for the benefit of those that might be listening to this, I was pointing to the mail on the desk over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: This wants me to pick these things, and this is ridiculous.
[SPEAKER_01]: We have our opinions.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mentioned, while the tape was off, about Cy Marshall, how I interviewed him, you know, you were with him in Memphis.
[SPEAKER_02]: A little bit about the manager of that team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I don't know too much about Mike Donovan.
[SPEAKER_01]: I knew that he was married to Mabel Hite, who was one of the great actresses of her day.
[SPEAKER_02]: He went on to stage, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, and afterwards did very well in motion pictures after he was with Memphis.
[SPEAKER_01]: But what actually happened down there, Mike was a tough guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was married to a very lovely girl.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know her name.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was McGraw's bodyguard in one way.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a pretty good ball player too, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, damn right he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit .368.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he a Hall of Fame material?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not that good one.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think he played that long in the big league.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was one heck of a ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it came one Sunday, it's an interesting story, it came one Sunday down there, I think it was a Sunday, and it was raining.
[SPEAKER_01]: his best pitcher pitching, I forget who it was, but the uh... it was and uh... the umpires wouldn't call the game and uh...
[SPEAKER_01]: I think, I don't know whether we were ahead or the other team was ahead, I don't know who was ahead but the umpires insisted on playing so Mike called his pitcher out of there and to show up the umpires, he went in and pitched and uh... of course the other team scored about fourteen runs off him and uh...
[SPEAKER_01]: The stands were very close and Mike was a profane guy and he had a profane argument with one of the umpires and he was let go the next day and me along with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I pitched well down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I lost 3 to 2 and 2 to nothing in scores like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Dazzy Vance shut me out three times and all this sort of thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had Dazzy Vance, I think, beating 1 to nothing in the ninth inning and struck out the last guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the catcher, Schmitty, allowed the ball to get to the grandstand.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the tying run scored from third base.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they eventually beat us.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd like to put this away.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think that'll be...